Fred Carstensen Papers 1997.0085
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Fred Carstensen Papers
undated, 1973-1995.
1997.0085
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
2.3 Linear feet
Fred Carstensen is a Professor of Economics at the University of Connecticut. The collection documents University committees and programs with which he was invovled.
Carstensen, Fred.
Biography
A Professor of Economics at the University of Connecticut, Fred V. Carstensen received his graduate training at Yale University (M.A. 1969, Ph.D. 1976). He joined the faculty at UConn in 1982 and the focus of his research is business history.
Specific information regarding Dr. Carstensen's career and research interests are available here.
Scope and Content
The collection contains documents of activities, events and programs associated with the University in which Dr. Carstensen was involved.
Arrangement
The materials are described as received.
Series I: Inventory ( undated, 1973-1995 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut business records, as well as the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated by Dr. Carstensen in March 1997.
Carstensen, Fred.; University of Connecticut.; Administrative Records.; Bylaws.; Correspondence.; Educator.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Newspapers.; Notes.; University of Connecticut--Administration.; University of Connecticut--Faculty--Professional and personal papers.
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1973-1995
  - University of Connecticut Foundation Assessment of Financials Accounting Operations 1985 with Board of Trustees minutes (Box 1)
  - University of Connecticut Foundation Cash Management and Investment Practices Review draft, 1985 (Box 1)
  - University of Connecticut Foundation Manual of Fiscal Policies and Procedures, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Handbook Transactions with the University of Connecticut Foundation, 1990 (Box 1)
  - University of Connecticut Fact Book from the Office of Institutional Research, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Program Review Committee Recommendations for meeting budget deficit for FY 94, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Coventry Historian with History of Coventry, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Library Advisory Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - Touching Your Life and Our World: Research at the University of Connecticut, undated (Box 1)
  - The UConn Fund A Margin for Excellence, undated (Box 1)
  - Program Review Committee Recommendations for meeting budget deficit for FY 94, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Provost: Economic Impact, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Teaching Initiative, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Budget Committee, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Waterbury, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Strategic Plan to Ensure Racial and Ethnic Diversity in Connecticut Puplic Higher Education, Access and Retention Plans, Letter to the peer review committee, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - University Senate Growth and Development Committee meeting minutes, 1991 November 11 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report of the Growth and Development committee, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Subcommittee on Undergraduate Retention, 1992 April 3undated (Box 1)
  - Growth and development sub committee, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Growth and development committee resolution and Minutes of the University Senate, undated, 1982 October 11 (Box 1)
  - Growth and development committee minutes, 1990 December 14 (Box 1)
  - Information for the Growth and development committee, undated (Box 1)
  - University of Connecticut Second Century Fund Museum of Natural History, Report: Status on the Natural History Proposal, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence re: Growth and development subcommittee, undated (Box 1)
  - Calendar - the creation of an electronic calendar for the university, undated (Box 1)
  - Reports and information about the Stamford campus, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Subcommittee on University of Connecticut Foundation, undated (Box 1)
  - Advisory committee information and reports, 1984-1989 (Box 1)
  - University Senate Growth and Development Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - Faculty/Staff development, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Annual report by the Growth and Development committee, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of Growth and Development committee, 1990 October 17 (Box 1)
  - Growth and Development Committee, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Class Scheduling, undated (Box 1)
  - Foundation Review, undated (Box 1)
  - Foundation and development sub committee, undated (Box 1)
  - Annual reports, 1976-1980 (Box 1)
  - UConn Foundation, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Information from committees with materials from other universities, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Admissions data, undated, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Sample Letters, undated (Box 2)
  - UConn Advance, 1983 September 8 (Box 2)
  - Report - "Demographic Changes and Their Impact on Enrollment in Connecticut Higher Education 1983-2000,", undated (Box 2)
  - Recruitment information, undated (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - S. Ray Study, undated (Box 2)
  - Information from Trinity College, Hartford, CT, undated (Box 2)
  - Admissions Reports, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Fine Arts, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Honors Program, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Social Science, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Humanities, 1984 (Box 2)
  - CLAS-Sciences, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Day of Pride, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Engineering, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Regional Campuses, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Agricultural/Natural Resources, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Reports on the University of Connecticut Foundation for the Growth and Development committee, undated (Box 3)
  - UConn Fund A Margin for Excellence folder with information for telemarketing, undated (Box 3)
  - UConn Foundation, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - University of Connecticut Foundation Manual of Fiscal Policies and Procedures, 1989 (Box 3)
  - By Laws, undated (Box 3)
  - University of Connecticut Foundation Report on Organization and Operations, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Organization Study of the University of Connecticut Foundation [draft], 1986 (Box 3)
  - University of Connecticut Foundation Strategic Planning Diagnostic Review, 1985 (Box 3)
  - UConn Racism, undated (Box 3)
  - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Fee Budget, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Subcommittee Notes and minutes, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Second Century Fund Report, 1987 Fall (Box 3)
  - Wolff (program in entrepreneurship), undated (Box 3)
  - Reforms, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Strategic Planning Management Committe, undated (Box 3)
  - Report of the Senate Review Panel concerning the Report of the Program Review Committee, undated (Box 3)
  - Grad Student Univ. Fee Comm, 1992 February 7 (Box 3)
  - VP External Affairs, undated (Box 3)